A Guide to the Papers Relating to Ezra Loomis Pound, 1958-1959
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Papers Relating to Ezra Pound 1958-1959
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
6272
This collection consists of 39 items.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
This collection was a gift of James J. Kilpatrick on April 20, 1960.
Scope and Content Information
Correspondence of Kilpatrick and Pound, and articles by Pound as "Foreign correspondent" for the Richmond News Leader. Other materials include: correspondence between Kilpatrick and Harry M. Meacham; copies of correspondence between Meacham and Ernest Hemingway and Archibald MacLeish; photographs of Pound and Meacham; interviews; and, newspaper clippings.
Contents List
- Harry Meacham to James J. Kilpatrick 1958 February 10, 1 p. TLS
- James J. Kilpatrick to Harry Meacham 1958 February 10, 1 p. TL carbon
- James J. Kilpatrick to Harry Meacham 1958 February 28, 1 p. TL carbon
- Harry Meacham to Washington Star1958 March 17, 2 p. TL carbon
- T.D. Horton to James J. Kilpatrick with press release, 1958 April 17, "Defenders Back Release of Ezra Pound" [1958 April], 1 p. 6 p. TLS
- Harry Meacham to James J. Kilpatrick 1958 April 17, 1 p. TLS
- James J. Kilpatrick interview with Ezra Pound with notes by [Ezra Pound] 1958 April 21, 1 p. 2 p. TM
- Harry Meacham to Ezra Pound 1958 April 26, 1 p. TL carbon
- Harry Meacham to James J. Kilpatrick 1958 April 28, 1 p. TLS
- "A Conversation With Ezra Pound" by James J. Kilpatrick [1958 April 30], 7 p. TM
- Ezra Pound to James J. Kilpatrick [1958] MAY 7, 2 p. TLS
- James J. Kilpatrick to Ezra Pound 1958 MAY 9, 2 p. TL carbon
- Harry Meacham to James J. Kilpatrick 1958 MAY 10, 1 p. TLS
- Ezra Pound to James J. Kilpatrick [1958] MAY 12, 1 p. TLS
- James J. Kilpatrick to Ezra Pound 1958 MAY 28, 1 p. TL carbon
- Ezra Pound to James J. Kilpatrick [1958] June 3, 1 p. TL
- James J. Kilpatrick to Ezra Pound 1958 June 5, 1 p. TL carbon
- Ezra Pound to James J. Kilpatrick [1958] June 5, 1 p. TL
- Ezra Pound to James J. Kilpatrick [1958 June], 1 p. TLS
- "Il Poeta Ezra Pound e arrivat..." [1958] July 13, 1 p. Newsclip
- "First Impressions" by Ezra Pound [1958] July 16, 2 p. TM
- "REzra Poundercussions" by Ezra Pound with PS to James J. Kilpatrick 1958 November 9, 1 p. 1 p. TM
- "European Response to American Election..." by Ezra Pound [1958] November 21, 1 p. TM
- Ezra Pound to James J. Kilpatrick 1958 November 25, 1 p. TLS
- [Ezra Pound] to James J. Kilpatrick [1958] November 25, 1 p. TL
- "Italian Renaissance" by [Ezra Pound] 1958 December 31, 1 p. TM
- Walter P. Guzzardi, Jr. to James J. Kilpatrick 1958 December 31, 1 p. TLS
- [Ezra Pound] to [James J. Kilpatrick] [1958 ? 17], 1 p. TL
- "They Did It" by Ezra Pound [1958], 1 p. TMS
- James J. Kilpatrick to Walter P. Guzzardi, Jr. 1958 January 5, 1 p. TL carbon
- "The Mind of Europe" by Ezra Pound [1958] MAY 8, 1 p. TMS
- Ezra Pound to [James J. Kilpatrick] [1958] MAY 15, 1 p. TLS
- "Permanent Plebiscit Campaign" by Ezra Pound 1959 June 13, 1 p. TM
- Ezra Pound to James J. Kilpatrick with press release 1959 June 10 [1959] June 15, 1 p. with envelope; 2 p. TLS
- James J. Kilpatrick to Ezra Pound 1959 July 6, 1 p. TL carbon
- James J. Kilpatrick to Marvin Mobley with TL carbon, 1959 June 6, A.S. Coody to Judge Boyd Sloan 1959 July 6, 1 p. TL carbon
- Harry Meacham to James J. Kilpatrick 1959 July 7, 1 p. ALS
- James J. Kilpatrick to Harry Meacham 1959 July 8, 1 p. TL carbon
- Ezra Pound to James J. Kilpatrick 1959 July 9, 1 p. TLS
- Photographs of Ezra Pound and Harry Meacham.